# Ravi R. Joshi

👚 4950 Stevenson Blvd, Fremont, CA, USA-94538

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/rrjoshi

**\(\sum\_{+1}\)** +1 510-458-8560

rrjoshi92@gmail.com

## **Profile:**

Result-oriented Web Developer with over 3 years of cumulative work experience in designing, implementing and testing industry-leading Enterprise Integration Web Application. Productive in both team-based and self-managed projects; dedicated to maintaining up-to-date industry knowledge and software skills.

## **Education:**

**Northwestern Polytechnic University** 

[August 2015 – December 2016]

✓ Master of Computer Science

[June 2009 - May 2013]

**Gujarat Technological University** 

✓ Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

# **Technical Skills:**

Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, C#, ASP.NET, JSON, AJAX, SASS

- Frameworks: AngularJS, BackboneJS, MVC5, Bootstrap, Three tier architecture, Entity Framework, Progress Sitefinity
- Methodologies: Object Oriented Programming/Design, Design Pattern
- Database: MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, MS-SQL
- Development Tools: Sublime text 3, Visual Studio 2015, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse IDE, NetBeans IDE, GIT, TFS, Radar

# **Work Experience:**

✓ UI Engineer, B2B Event Web-Application – Apple

[August 2016 - Current]

[Backbone.JS, JavaScript, JQuery, SASS, Bootstrap, Grunt, HTML, Datatables.JS, RESTful API]

As a part of UI team at Apple I was Involved in design, development, and enhancement of various modules of the application. Used java script framework for implementing popups, dropdown, toolbar, tables, reflow-layout, search, events, and navigation controller for enhancing dashboard, widgets, sidebar, case details and related views. I was responsible for developing views using Backbone.js, Marionette.js framework from design mockups. Worked on DataTableJS for displaying events, scheduling, planning, attachment, contacts modules for education and conferences markets. I was also responsible for UI build process, documentation and radar updates. Active communication with offshore team and task assignment.

Software Engineer, Marketing Website - Cygnet Infotech [Microsoft Partner] [July 2013 - August 2014] [ASP.NET, C#, HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap, RESTful API, Ajax, JQuery, JavaScript, JSON, Progress Sitefinity]

Designed drag and drop MVC widget in C# which acts as signup funnel using API and integration of HTML pages. Website was built for corporate marketing purpose for international users. It was created using Progress Sitefinity as a front-end that allows marketing team to handle the contents of the different pages that are used for marketing of different products of the company. Applied my knowledge of CSS, HTML, and JavaScript to implement web based user interfaces that are responsive to rendering and viewing in multiple different form factors (laptop, tablet, smart phones).

✓ Intern, E-commerce Online Shopping system - Cygnet Infotech [Microsoft Partner] [ASP.NET, C#, HTML 5, CSS 3, Bootstrap, Ajax, JQuery, JavaScript, JSON]

[June 2012 - July 2013]

As an Intern at Cygnet InfoTech I have developed E-commerce portal using C# .NET, HTML, CSS, ADO.NET and MS-SQL. Developed order and customer management modules. From UX design and developed the HTML, CSS and build related JavaScript (D3, jQuery ) in order to bring the design to life as primary responsibility. Used AJAX calls to update data on the page. I have also designed MS-SQL database and written stored procedures for all database transections.

#### **Academic Projects**

## Pro-Shop-Build and Buy [T-shirt customization]

[Fall 2016]

[AngularJS, PHP, Code ignitor, HTML-5, SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, Fabricis, RESTful API, My-SQL]

It is a T-shirt store where customer can design their own T-shirt and order. The application uses APIs developed in PHP and stores data into MySQL. Frontend is developed in HTML JQuery and for T-shirt customization we used Fabricjs library. Application has nice admin panel too which is also developed in PHP and UI is developed in HTML 5 and CSS 3.

# **➢** GitHub Viewer

[Spring 2016]

[AngularJS, HTML 5, CSS-3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery]

It was a self-inspired Single Page Application [SPA], developed in AngularJS framework to sharpen my knowledge on AngularJS. Integrated GitHub public API to fetch data from GitHub. Application will search user from username and list all repositories. Created factory in AngularJS to filter and sort fetched repositories by primary language and stars given to that repository.

# **Leadership & Achievements**

- ✓ <u>Microsoft:</u> 10267A: Introduction to Web Development with Microsoft Visual Studio 2010
- ✓ Web Development: Certificate of Advanced course in Software Engineering .net 4.0
- ✓ JAVA: Certificate of 6 months training in core java

# **Activities and Interests**

- > Aviation: Familiar with most procedure of commercial jet flying.
- Virtual Flying: Member of VatSim community and have 500 online flying hours.